<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Progress Reports on Abhinav Potineni</title>
    <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Progress Reports on Abhinav Potineni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Progress Report 2: Machine Learning Courses</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/phase2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/phase2/</guid>
      <description>4/16 - Received completion certificate for “Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra” course offered by the Imperial College London on Coursera
5/2 - Received completion certificate for “Mathematics for Machine Learning: Multivariate Calculus” course offered by the Imperial College London on Coursera
5/8 - Uploaded all Signature 3 materials into &amp;ldquo;Signature 3 Video and Paper&amp;rdquo; folder. The folder contained the Signature 3 Video, Junior Research Project Background Paper, FHS Dataset, Presentation Slideshow, and Rudimentary COde</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress Report 1: Researcher Meetings</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/report-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/report-2/</guid>
      <description>SUMMARY:
To help get an understanding of whether or not my project was feasible as well as what steps I would need to take in order to get my data in a useable form, I reached out to researchers who were well situated with the dataset. I asked them questions regarding the potential limitations of the dataset with regards to ethnic background, ML models used on it in the past specifically regarding Cardiovascular Diseases, Limitations of Previous Research, and areas of interests for scientists currently working in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
