<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scene on Abhinav Potineni</title>
    <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/tags/scene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scene on Abhinav Potineni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/tags/scene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Progress Report 2: Machine Learning Courses</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/phase2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/phase2/</guid>
      <description>4/16 - Received completion certificate for “Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra” course offered by the Imperial College London on Coursera
5/2 - Received completion certificate for “Mathematics for Machine Learning: Multivariate Calculus” course offered by the Imperial College London on Coursera
5/8 - Uploaded all Signature 3 materials into &amp;ldquo;Signature 3 Video and Paper&amp;rdquo; folder. The folder contained the Signature 3 Video, Junior Research Project Background Paper, FHS Dataset, Presentation Slideshow, and Rudimentary COde</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Machine Learning?</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/meetings/sdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/meetings/sdesign/</guid>
      <description>Before delving into the specific Machine Learning Applications, it&amp;rsquo;s also crucial to look into why a project would be needed in this area.
As mentioned previously, the variations in early signs and symptoms make CHD harder to recognize. As such, it&amp;rsquo;s important to look into preventative rather than reactive measures. Looking into a patient&amp;rsquo;s risk factors and using them to determine whether they would be at risk of CHD in the next decade allows significant room for lifestyle changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting 2: Dr. Emelia Benjamin (Boston University Professor)</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/post/nkvk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:33:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/post/nkvk/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Emelia J. Benjamin is a Professor of Medicine and Epidimiology at Boston University and a clinical cardiologist at Boston Medical Center. She has authored 650+ peer-reviewed publications that focus on genetics, epidimiology, and prognosis of a variety of cardiovascular conditions and markers.
Her Info: https://www.bumc.bu.edu/busm/profile/emelia-benjamin/
Recorded Meeting Link: https://youtu.be/9VY0MVqqVF0
Transcript Link: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HEyFEZ2ez7TYBYVaX6pbFfVMWVHmAGX_ZqzEp_BokE4/edit?usp=sharing
Main Points Made:
Limitations:
 The Framingham study does not reflect the ethnic and racial diversity of our country today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting 3: Dr. Alvin Ang AND Harvard ML Researcher</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/post/tfaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/post/tfaa/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Emelia J. Benjamin is a Professor of Medicine and Epidimiology at Boston University and a clinical cardiologist at Boston Medical Center. She has authored 650+ peer-reviewed publications that focus on genetics, epidimiology, and prognosis of a variety of cardiovascular conditions and markers.
Her Info: https://www.bumc.bu.edu/busm/profile/emelia-benjamin/
Recorded Meeting Link: https://youtu.be/9VY0MVqqVF0
Transcript Link: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HEyFEZ2ez7TYBYVaX6pbFfVMWVHmAGX_ZqzEp_BokE4/edit?usp=sharing
Main Points Made:
Limitations:
 The Framingham study does not reflect the ethnic and racial diversity of our country today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framingham Heart Study Dataset</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/meetings/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/meetings/dataset/</guid>
      <description>DATASET USED
 The dataset that I&amp;rsquo;m using is the Framingham Heart Study (FHS) Dataset from the NHLBI or BioLinCC website.
For more information about how the data was collected, visit the &amp;ldquo;Framingham Heart Study Design&amp;rdquo; tab under Background
Dataset Specifics:
 Image of the .csv file (Open in New Tab)   Above is a portion of how the .csv file of the dataset looks like, with less important feature columns not included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress Report 1: Researcher Meetings</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/report-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/goals/report-2/</guid>
      <description>SUMMARY:
To help get an understanding of whether or not my project was feasible as well as what steps I would need to take in order to get my data in a useable form, I reached out to researchers who were well situated with the dataset. I asked them questions regarding the potential limitations of the dataset with regards to ethnic background, ML models used on it in the past specifically regarding Cardiovascular Diseases, Limitations of Previous Research, and areas of interests for scientists currently working in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase II: Merging of Data Types and Image Generation using GANS</title>
      <link>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/projectsummary/phase2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahinbav.github.io/CHD-Research/projectsummary/phase2/</guid>
      <description>Phase 3 and 4: Merging of Data Types and Image Generation using GANS
The second phase of my project is merging data types. One of the researchers that I talked to suggested this. For a project regarding prediction of Parkinson’s disease, he used GANS or GANS: Generative Adversarial Networks to augment his dataset since he didn’t have enough images. Given a training set, this technique learns to generate new data with the same statistics as the training set.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
